

CONTACT

- (+91) 8475962723
- New Delhi, India
- mindgo.sharma@gmail.com
- 5 Years O Month of experience

EDUCATION

2017

B.Tech/B.E. - Computers

Uttarakhand Technical University College of Engineering Roorkee

Grade - 70%

2012

XIIth

Bihar, English Marks - 70-74.9%

2009

Xth

Bihar, English Marks - 70-74.9%

KEYSKILLS

React-native

AMAN SHARMA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER-II

PROFILE SUMMARY

Having overall and react-native working experience of around 5 yrs, I'm looking forward to an opportunity to work in a dynamic environment where I can utilize my skills for developing my career and for the growth of the organization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2022 -2024 Software Development EngineerII

Cardekho Group

I was working as Software Development Engineer-II, Develop Cross Platform App(iOS & Android).

2020 -2022 React Native Developer
New Media Guru Pvt Ltd

I was working as React Native Developer, Develop Cross Platform App(iOS & Android)

2019 -2020

Software Engineer Affle

I was working as Software Engineer, Develop Cross Platform App(iOS & Android). Javascript
React.js
Redux
Redux Middleware
Redux Toolkit

PROJECTS

CarDekho Group(Mar 2022-Apr 2024)

8 Months

1.LMS

About Projects: It's app for both the platform(Android & iOS) to create leads and manage leads of new car purchase in South East Asia.

Tools & Technologies: It was developed by using React Native, JavaScript, React, React hooks, Higher Order Component, Context Api, Render Props, Realm, Firebase, Rest Api, Third parties Api, Unit Testing(Jest) and Jira.

Roles & Responsibilites:

i.Write clean, efficient, and maintainable code using JavaScript and the React Native framework.

ii.Build cross-platform applications for iOS and Android from a single codebase.

iii.Implement RESTful APIs to connect the application with backend services.

iv. Handle third-party API integrations such as payment gateways, social media, and analytics services

v. Optimize application performance to ensure smooth user experiences.

App Links:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.girnarsoft.zwph&pcampaignid=web_shar e AND https://apps.apple.com/in/app/zigwheelscars-bikes/id704453976

2.SFA

10 Months

About Project: It's app for both the platform(Android & iOS) for managing loan and insurance of used car in South East Asia.

Tools & Technologies: It was developed by using React Native, JavaScript, React, React hooks, Higher Order Component, Context Api, Render Props, Realm, Firebase, Rest Api, Third parties Api, Unit Testing(Jest) and Jira.

Roles & Responsibilites:

i.Write clean, efficient, and maintainable code using JavaScript and the React Native framework.

ii.Build cross-platform applications for iOS and Android from a single codebase.

iii.Implement RESTful APIs to connect the application with backend services.

Context API

Higher Order Component(Custom HOC)

Render Props

Firebase

Push Notification

Deep Linking

CI/CD Pipeline(App Center & CodePush)

Debugging Tool(React Developer Tool)

Performance Testing and Debugging Tool(Flipper)

Unit Testing(Jest)

JIRA Tool

GIT

MySQL

SQL

MySQL Workbench

Rest Api

JSON

HTML

CSS

LANGUAGE

HINDI

ENGLISH



SOCIAL LINKS

https://www.linkedin.com/in/aman-sharma-5475901ba/

iv.Handle third-party API integrations such as payment gateways, social media, and analytics services

v.Optimize application performance to ensure smooth user experiences.

App Links:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.int.sfa&pcampaignid=web_share AND https://apps.apple.com/in/app/otosfa/id1489698573

3.Dealer App

8 Months

About Project: It's app for both the platform(Android & iOS) for managing dealer in South East Asia.

Tools & Technologies: It was developed by using React Native, JavaScript, React, React hooks, Higher Order Component, Context Api, Render Props, Realm, Firebase, Rest Api, Third parties Api, Unit Testing(Jest) and Jira.

Roles & Responsibilites:

i.Write clean, efficient, and maintainable code using JavaScript and the React Native framework.

ii.Build cross-platform applications for iOS and Android from a single codebase.

iii.Implement RESTful APIs to connect the application with backend services.

iv. Handle third-party API integrations such as payment gateways, social media, and analytics services

v.Optimize application performance to ensure smooth user experiences.

App Links:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.oto.dealer.id&pcampaignid=web_share AND https://apps.apple.com/in/app/otodealer/id1489698884

New Media Guru Pvt Ltd(Nov 2020-March 2022)

8 Months

1.Wealth Concert

About Project: It's app for both the platform(Android & iOS) for creating committee and fund distribution online.

Tools & Technologies: It was developed by using Tools & Technologies React Native, JavaScript, React, React hooks, Redux, Redux Thunk, Firebase, Rest Api, Third parties Api and Jira.

Roles & Responsibilites:

i.Write clean, efficient, and maintainable code using JavaScript and the React Native framework.

ii.Build cross-platform applications for iOS and Android from a single codebase.

iii.Implement RESTful APIs to connect the application with backend services.

iv. Handle third-party API integrations such as payment gateways, social media, and analytics services

v.Optimize application performance to ensure smooth user experiences.

App Links:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.noblefolks.wealthconcertandroid&pcam paignid=web_share AND https://apps.apple.com/in/app/wealthconcert/id1576513504

2.Vouch

7 Months

About Project: It's app for both the platform(Android & iOS) to create and share feed like Instagram.

Tools & Technologies: It was developed by using Tools & Technologies React Native, JavaScript, React, React hooks, Redux, Redux Thunk, Firebase, Rest Api, Third parties Api and Jira.

Roles & Responsibilites:

i.Write clean, efficient, and maintainable code using JavaScript and the React Native framework.

ii.Build cross-platform applications for iOS and Android from a single codebase.

iii.Implement RESTful APIs to connect the application with backend services.

iv. Handle third-party API integrations such as payment gateways, social media, and analytics services

v. Optimize application performance to ensure smooth user experiences.

Affle Inida Ltd(Apr 2019-Oct 2020)

8 Months

1.Niine

About Project: It's a Mobile application for both the platform(Android & iOS), in this girls or women can track their next period date by

logging their previous date and can also find their ovulation period.

Tools & Technologies: It was developed by using Tools & Technologies React Native, JavaScript, React, Higher Order Component, Firebase, Rest Api, Third parties Api and Jira.

Roles & Responsibilites:

i.Write clean, efficient, and maintainable code using JavaScript and the React Native framework.

ii.Build cross-platform applications for iOS and Android from a single codebase.

iii.Implement RESTful APIs to connect the application with backend services.

iv. Handle third-party API integrations such as payment gateways, social media, and analytics services

v.Optimize application performance to ensure smooth user experiences.

App Links:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.girnarsoft.zwph&pcampaignid=web_shar e

2.Sunny E-Store

6 Months

About Project: It's a E-Commerce Mobile Application for both the platform(Android & iOS), sells electronic gadgets.

Tools & Technologies: It was developed by using Tools & Technologies React Native, JavaScript, React, Higher Order Component, Firebase, Rest Api, Third parties Api and Jira.

Roles & Responsibilites:

i.Write clean, efficient, and maintainable code using JavaScript and the React Native framework.

ii.Build cross-platform applications for iOS and Android from a single codebase.

iii.Implement RESTful APIs to connect the application with backend services.

iv. Handle third-party API integrations such as payment gateways, social media, and analytics services

v.Optimize application performance to ensure smooth user experiences.

3. Funda E-Learning

6 Months

About Project: It's an mediators app for both the platform(Android & iOS) between tutor and



student, in this app student can book their sessions for resolving doubts and tutor can place bid to their respective sessions.

Tools & Technologies: It was developed by using Tools & Technologies React Native, JavaScript, React, Higher Order Component, Firebase, Rest Api, Third parties Api and Jira. Roles & Responsibilites:

i.Write clean, efficient, and maintainable code using JavaScript and the React Native framework.

ii.Build cross-platform applications for iOS and Android from a single codebase. Implement.

iii.RESTful APIs to connect the application with backend services.

iv. Handle third-party API integrations such as payment gateways, social media, and analytics services.

v.Optimize application performance to ensure smooth user experiences.